<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<databaseChangeLog
    xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog
        https://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-4.20.xsd">
    <changeSet id="001-bootstrap-roles-and-schemas" author="demoapp" runOnChange="true">
        <sql splitStatements="false">
            -- Only use this for local - password have to be changed for real instances.
            -- Initialize MapMarkerDb: separate users and schemas for Keycloak and MapService
            -- This script runs as the bootstrap superuser (postgres).

            DO $$
            BEGIN
              IF NOT EXISTS (SELECT 1 FROM pg_catalog.pg_roles WHERE rolname = 'keycloak') THEN
                CREATE ROLE keycloak LOGIN PASSWORD 'keycloak';
              ELSE
                ALTER ROLE keycloak WITH LOGIN PASSWORD 'keycloak';
              END IF;
            END
            $$;

            DO $$
            BEGIN
              IF NOT EXISTS (SELECT 1 FROM information_schema.schemata WHERE schema_name = 'keycloak') THEN
                EXECUTE 'CREATE SCHEMA keycloak AUTHORIZATION keycloak';
              END IF;
            END
            $$;

            GRANT USAGE ON SCHEMA keycloak TO keycloak;
            GRANT CREATE ON SCHEMA keycloak TO keycloak;
            GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON ALL TABLES IN SCHEMA keycloak TO keycloak;
            GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON ALL SEQUENCES IN SCHEMA keycloak TO keycloak;
            ALTER DEFAULT PRIVILEGES FOR ROLE postgres IN SCHEMA keycloak GRANT ALL ON TABLES TO keycloak;
            ALTER DEFAULT PRIVILEGES FOR ROLE postgres IN SCHEMA keycloak GRANT ALL ON SEQUENCES TO keycloak;

            DO $$
            BEGIN
              IF NOT EXISTS (SELECT 1 FROM pg_catalog.pg_roles WHERE rolname = 'mapservice') THEN
                CREATE ROLE mapservice LOGIN PASSWORD 'mapservice';
              ELSE
                ALTER ROLE mapservice WITH LOGIN PASSWORD 'mapservice';
              END IF;
            END
            $$;

            DO $$
            BEGIN
              IF NOT EXISTS (SELECT 1 FROM information_schema.schemata WHERE schema_name = 'mapservice') THEN
                EXECUTE 'CREATE SCHEMA mapservice AUTHORIZATION mapservice';
              END IF;
            END
            $$;

            GRANT USAGE ON SCHEMA mapservice TO mapservice;
            GRANT CREATE ON SCHEMA mapservice TO mapservice;
            GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON ALL TABLES IN SCHEMA mapservice TO mapservice;
            GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON ALL SEQUENCES IN SCHEMA mapservice TO mapservice;
            ALTER DEFAULT PRIVILEGES FOR ROLE postgres IN SCHEMA mapservice GRANT ALL ON TABLES TO mapservice;
            ALTER DEFAULT PRIVILEGES FOR ROLE postgres IN SCHEMA mapservice GRANT ALL ON SEQUENCES TO mapservice;
        </sql>
    </changeSet>
</databaseChangeLog>
